Martin Buxbaum Papers
Martin Buxbaum Papers
1942-1991
Buxbaum, Martin.
11 linear ft.
American author, poet; director of communications for Marriott Corporation, 1953-1976, editor of Hot Shoppes Table Talk and various in-house publications. Collection contains correspondence, incoming and outgoing (1937-1967); manuscript books, essays, poems, short stories, speeches; photographs; and printed material, including articles by and about Buxbaum, clippings, and house organs edited by Buxbaum for several companies for which he worked.
148881
Biographical History
Martin Buxbaum (1912-1991) was an American poet, author and editor. Born in Richmond, Virginia, Buxbaum was blind but underwent a cataract operation which restored his sight. As Director of Communications for Marriott Corporation, he edited their monthly publication Table Talk for many years and received much acclaim for it. After retiring Buxbaum went on to write eleven books, including Rivers of Thought and The Underside of Heaven, and became known as a photographer, artist and humorist. He and his wife Alice had eight children. [Family information obtained from Buxbaum's granddaughter.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Martin Buxbaum Papers consists of biographical material, correspondence, subject files, manuscripts and published material.
Biographical material consists of a biographical sketch.
Correspondence, subdivided into business and personal, is mostly incoming with only a small amount of outgoing.
Subject files include book covers, Christmas cards, photographs, and two audiotapes.
Manuscripts includes those of books, magazine articles, poems, short stories, speeches and other items.
Published material contains a first edition of Buxbaum's book Rivers of Thought along with fliers, magazines with articles both by and about Buxbaum, and news clippings.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection comprises two separate accessions which have not been physically integrated; related material may therefore be scattered across several boxes. To simplify locating all relevant material, the inventory below lists the contents of the collection in logical, not physical, order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Buxbaum, Martin.; Marriott Corporation -- Publishing.; Marriott Hot Shoppes.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; Customer relations.; House organs.; Poets, American.; Hotels -- Public relations.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Essays.; House organs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Poems.; Speeches (documents); Authors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Awards (Box 6)
  - Biographical sketch (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957; 1959,; 1965-1967,; undated; includes some published material (Box 6)
- Correspondence
  - Books, Inc., 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Guideposts, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
  - Quality Industries, 1959; 1965-1966,; undated (Box 6)
  - Sunshine Press, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Re: The Unsung
    - Incoming, 1963-1966; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Outgoing, 1966; undated (Box 6)
    - Envelopes, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Incoming
    - Business, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Personal, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - General, 1953; 1956-1961,; 1963-1965; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - General, 1966-1967; 5 folders (Box 8)
    - Unidentified, includes Buxbaum family correspondence (Box 8)
    - Greeting cards, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Outgoing
    - Miscellaneous, 1937; 1964,; undated (Box 2)
- Subject files
  - Book covers (Box 2)
  - Bookmarks (Box 2)
  - Christmas cards (Box 2)
  - Invitation to commissioning of U.S.S. Tecumseh (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, two sketches, two unidentified photographs (Box 13)
  - Photographs of Buxbaum and his books (Box 2)
  - Tapes, "Red Cross" and "Poems" (Box 2)
- Manuscripts
  - Books
    - Rivers of Thought
      - Final draft (Box 2)
      - Printer's copy, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 9)
    - Sing a Song of Sexpence, chapters 1 and 2, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 9)
    - Table Talk for Family Fun
      - Printer's copy, with revisions (Box 9)
      - Galleys, with revisions (Box 9)
    - The Underside of Heaven
      - Artist's page layout (Box 9)
      - Book fragments, page proofs (Box 9)
      - Layout (holograph and printed), 2 folders (Box 2)
    - The Unsung
      - Artist's page layout (Box 9)
      - Biographies of contributors, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Poetry, typescript with manuscript revisions; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Poetry rejections, typescript and holographs; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Final draft, by others (Box 2)
      - Final draft, by others (Box 3)
      - Galleys, includes a sketch; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Galleys, with manuscript revisions (Box 11)
      - Printer's copy, typescript with manuscript revisions; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Whispers in the Wind
      - Drafts, typescript with revisions; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Page proofs (Box 11)
      - Galleys with manuscript revisions (Box 11)
    - Unidentified, possibly Rivers of Thought or The Underside of Heaven; printer's copy with manuscript revisions (Box 11)
  - Essays
    - Around Our House, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 11)
    - Reflections, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, titled, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, untitled, typescript with manuscript revisions; holographs (Box 12)
  - Magazines
    - The Southern Diaries with comments by others (Box 3)
  - Memoranda
    - Miscellaneous, typescript with manuscript revisions (Box 12)
  - Notes and sketches
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Poems
    - A-W and untitled, rough drafts, holograph (Box 3)
    - A-W and untitled, rough drafts, typescript (Box 3)
    - from Whispers in the Wind, first draft (Box 3)
    - Titled, typescript with manuscript revisions; holographs (Box 12)
    - Untitled, typescript with manuscript revisions; holographs (Box 12)
  - Speeches
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Short stories
    - Published, B-T and untitled, typescript (Box 3)
    - Unpublished, B-T and untitled, typescript (Box 3)
  - Of others
    - Buxbaum children, typescript (Box 12)
- Published material
  - Books
    - Bux's Scrapbook (Box 4)
    - History of Fairfield (Box 13)
    - Rivers of Thought (Box 4)
    - Table Talk for Family Fun (Box 4)
    - Underside of Heaven (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967; undated; book-related items: book covers, articles about his books, photograph, etc. (Box 13)
  - Fliers
    - Advertisements for The Unsung (Box 4)
  - Magazines
    - Articles about Buxbaum (Box 4)
    - Articles by Buxbaum (Box 4)
    - Articles about others (Box 4)
    - Bux's Scrapbook (Box 4)
  - News clippings
    - Articles about Buxbaum (Box 4)
    - Articles by Buxbaum (Box 5)
  - Newsletters
    - Articles about Buxbaum (Box 5)
    - Edited by Buxbaum, Table Talk (Box 5)
    - Edited by Buxbaum, 1960-1966; Table Talk; Management Newsletter (Box 13)
  - Poems
    - Magazines and booklets (Box 5)
    - "Found in Cookbook" (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953; 1958,; 1960-1967,; undated (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Baseball for Doodlers, pencil-and-paper game designed by Buxbaum (Box 13)
    - Buxbaum-related items, 1958-1967; undated (Box 13)
    - Unrelated items, 1882; 1960-1967,; undated (Box 13)